Enums, or enumerations, are a way to express that a value can be one out of a finite set of possible values,
枚举是一种表示值可以是有限可能值集合中的一个的方式，
such as one of the suits in a deck of playing cards.
例如一副扑克牌中的花色之一。
Enums are one of the ways of defining custom types in Rust. Structs are the other,
枚举是Rust中定义自定义类型的一种方式。另一种是结构体，
and we'll be covering structs in the next module.
我们将在下一节介绍结构体。
We're going to be using some of the primitive data types we covered in module 4,
我们将使用一些在第4讲过的基本数据类型，
and we'll show how enums work
我们将展示
especially well with the match expression that we covered in module 6 about control flow.
枚举是如何很好地与第6讲控制流时讲过的匹配表达式一起工作的。
In this module, first,
在本节中，首先，
we'll talk a bit more about when enums are useful.
我们将多讨论一下枚举在什么情况下是有用的。
Then, we'll look at the syntax for defining and using enums in Rust.
然后，我们将了解在Rust中定义和使用枚举的语法。
We'll see how we can define enum variants that hold data,
我们将看到如何定义保存数据的枚举变量，
and we'll wrap up the module by looking at some examples of enums used with match expressions.
并通过查看与匹配表达式一起使用枚举的一些示例来结束该模块。
Let's start with an example of when enums are useful.
让我们从一个枚举挺有用的例子开始。
Let's say we're writing a program having to do with ice hockey. In hockey,
假设我们正在编写一个与冰球有关的程序。在冰球比赛中，
there are different positions
球员可以打不同的位置：
a player can play: center, wing, defense,
中锋、边锋、后卫或
or goalie.
守门员。
There are two aspects of this property of a player that make this a good case to model with an enum.
球员的这一属性有两个方面使其成为使用枚举建模的好例子。
First, a
首先，
player can only be in one of these positions at a time. While players may change positions,
玩家一次只能处于其中一个位置。虽然球员可能会改变位置，
they're not going to be in the goal and playing center at the same moment.
但他们不会同时站在球门和中锋位置。
Second,
其次，
we can list all the possibilities for the values of a position in ice hockey.
我们可以列出冰球中一个位置值的所有可能性。
There's a finite number of possible values,
可能的值是有限的，
and they don't change.
而且它们不会改变。
Our hockey program won't need to allow users to define new hockey positions.
另外我们的冰球程序不需要允许用户定义新的冰球位置。
Now that we've got a use case for an enum,
现在我们已经有了一个适合使用枚举的例子，
let's see how to define it
让我们看看如何在Rust代码中定义它。
We start with the enum keyword and then choose a name for the whole set.
我们从 enum 关键字开始，然后为整个集合选择一个名称。
In this case,
在本例中，
we're going to choose HockeyPosition.
我们选择 HockeyPosition 作为类型名。
Then, we put curly brackets and a comma-separated list of the possible values
然后，放入花括号和一个由逗号分隔的枚举可能具有的值列表。
the
枚举值名称
enum
这些被称为枚举的枚举值。
In this case,
在本例中，
we have variants for Center, Wing, Defense, and Goalie. Both enum names and
有Center（译者注：程序变量名不翻译），Wing，Defense 和 Goalie 这几种值。枚举类型名和
enum
枚举值名称
variant names are in camel case in idiomatic Rust.
习惯上以驼峰风格命名。
We've got a HockeyPosition type defined;
我们已经定义了一个HockeyPosition 类型变量。
let's look at how to use it!
让我们来看看如何使用它！
We can set a variable to have the value of one of the enum's variants by specifying the name of the enum, then two colons, then the variant.
我们可以通过指定枚举类型名、两个冒号和变量名来设置一个变量，使其具有枚举变量之一的值。
The enum variants are namespaced beneath the overall enum type.
枚举值的名称空间位于整个枚举类型的下面。
We can also define a function to take a HockeyPosition as a parameter,
还可以定义一个函数，将HockeyPosition类型作为形参，
and we can call that function and pass it a value of any of the enum's variants.
调用该函数并将枚举的任意值传递给它。
This function doesn't do anything –
这个函数不做任何事情——
we're just showing how the signature is written.
我们只是展示函数签名是如何写的。
Each enum
还可以定义
variant can also be defined to hold additional data.
每个枚举值来保存额外的数据
This is different for enums in languages like Java and C,
这与 Java 和 C 等语言中的枚举不同，
which can't hold additional data.
它们不能保存额外的数据。
Here's an enum that represents different kinds of clocks our program supports.
下面是一个枚举，它表示程序支持的不同类型的时钟。
Sundials only really have an hour value.
日晷只有一个关于小时的值。
The digital clocks we support only have hours and minutes.
这里写的数字时钟只有小时和分钟方面的值。
The analog clocks we support have an hour hand, a minute hand, and a second hand.
而这里的模拟时钟拥有时针，分针和秒针的概念。
Variants can hold multiple pieces of data. The parentheses are like a tuple.
枚举值可以保存多个数据。这里的括号类似元组。
Enum variants can also have named fields and look like a struct –  we'll be covering
枚举值还可以拥有命名字段，就想结构体一样，我们将在
structs in the next module.
下一节介绍结构体。
Finally,
最后，
let's see how enums and match expressions work well together.
让我们看看枚举和匹配表达式是如何很好地协同工作的。
Taking our clock example,
以我们的时钟程序为例，
let's write a function to print out the time in words,
让我们编写一个函数，打印出时间描述，
no matter what kind of clock we have.
不管我们有什么样的时钟。
This function has a parameter of a clock value.
这个函数有一个时钟类型的参数。
In the function, we'll match on that clock value and do something different
在函数中，我们将匹配同类型的时钟值，并根据不同的
based on which variant we have. Within each pattern of the match expression,
时种类型值做不同的事。在匹配表达式的每个模式中，
we can destructure the values each variant holds.
我们可以解构每个枚举值持有的数据。
For example,
例如，
in the Analog pattern,
例如，在 Analog 模式中，
we're creating the new variables – hours,
我们创建了新的变量(小时、分钟和秒) ，
minutes, and seconds – that matched the three u8 values held in that variant. In the code that goes with that pattern,
它们与该变量中保存的三个 u8值相匹配。在该模式下的代码中，
we can use those variables.
就可以使用这三个值。
This code prints
这段代码会打印，
It is 25 minutes and 45 seconds past 9 o'clock.
It is 25 minutes and 45 seconds past 9 o'clock.
Enums are great for defining types that can be one of a possible set of values.
枚举对于定义可能是一组值之一的类型非常有用。
They can optionally hold extra data,
还可以选择持有额外的数据，
and we can use match expressions to make decisions based on which variant we have, and use the patterns to destructure the values in the variants.
并在匹配表达式中根据匹配来做我们想做的操作，并使用模式来解构枚举值里持有的额外数据。
Next,
下一节，
we'll talk about another way to define custom data types – structs.
我们将讨论定义自定义数据类型的另一种方法——结构体。